calling is the case involving Nimbus
Apollo
versus US Bank National Association. So
we should have Mr. Rubi for the
appellent and Mr. Donovan on behalf of
the appeal.
>> So Mr. Rubot, you were just here.
>> Oh your [laughter]
Good morning, Mr. Rubine.
>> Now, just wait.
>> All right. How How much time would you
like to reserve?
>> Five minutes to five minutes.
>> All right. Whenever you're ready, Mr.
Rub, please proceed.
>> Um, this is a case involving a
foreclosure, and the appeal is about the
fact that, and I've never actually had
this happen, although I've been involved
in a lot of foreclosures.
Somehow or another, the clerk
issued the certificate of title.
Uh the sale was at uh 26. It's two days
in February. They issued on on on uh the
4th and not the 10 days that's required
by the statute. And in in inquiry to how
and why that happened, it turned out
that one of the orders that was entered
on a pre-sale objection that was filed
8:36 in the morning to just object to
the sale. We didn't want the sale to
take place at all. Um, and we had filed
an objection that the order that was
entered on that, which is actually
entered the next day, had an extra
paragraph in the bottom of it. And what
it said was, "The clerk is instructed to
complete the necessary steps towards
issuance of a certificate of title and
dispersement of funds to the final
judgment of foreclosure entered August
16th and pursuant to Florida law." See,
that paragraph shouldn't have been there
because the clerk took that to mean
because it says the clerk is instructed
to complete the necessary step
certificate of title. They do that
automatically. If there's a if you have
a foreclosure sale, unless a judge calls
down with the day to cancel it or unless
there's an order entered before that
date canceling it, they automatically
just go forward with the sale. And under
the statute, you have 10 days. You have
to file an objection within 10 days
after that sale is filed. And of course
you can have different objections based
on how much is bid, who bid, how much it
was, efficiency of sale, etc., etc. But
what happened here?
>> Let me ask you a threshold question
here. Your friend on the other side
suggests Your friend on the other side
suggests that this issue is not
preserved for review.
>> Is that what?
>> Preserved for review. You know what that
means, right?
>> Yes.
>> So can you I'm assuming you've read his
brief.
>> Yes.
>> Tell me about it. The reason it's
preserved for ref is because we made a
motion to rehear it with the court was
denied without a hearing. And that
shouldn't have happened because uh we
filed several we filed an objection. We
filed a motion to rehear. We filed a
motion to vacate. We filed three motions
directed to the court to add this hurt.
And under the case law I put in my
brief.
>> What did you do to try to get it set for
hearing? Because you know that a motion
for reharing is not guaranteed. A judge
can rule on that without having a
hearing. What did you do to get a
hearing set on it?
>> Well, we you know, we call up and try to
get you have to go through draws and
>> what do we have in our record that shows
that you tried to get a hearing?
>> I don't think there's anything on the
records. I request an evidentiary
hearing and I filed emotions for it to
be heard.
>> Wait, so there's a motion for that?
>> Yeah, I file a motion for evidentiary
hearing. I filed um I filed. Okay. So,
first of all um on the 20 um okay I
filed um motion to on 37205
and best before the end of the 10 days
that would have occurred. I filed a
motion to vacate certificate of sale
prematurely issued.
I also filed on the same date an
objection to sale and request for an
evidentiary hearing.
And then on 3:10, 3 days later, still
before, well, I think it would have ran
38, but I filed a motion for rehearing
and vacate order with attached copy of
order. That was within the 15 days. So,
I filed all three of those. Um,
uh, and then they um submitted these
orders uh through a cover letter which
attached it showed me served to Gabriel
Stre who was a prior attorney way before
me. Um and they gave form orders just
denying all of them in chambers without
a hearing. But the case law is very
clear under that um there's on my case I
got regard and that nre case um naker
case they're both very clear that the
statute that uh uh that what we're
operating under when you make an
objection like that there has to be a
hearing. It's required that you get a
hearing an evidence you're hearing or a
hearing and you can't just deny it
preonte like that. I mean, so I mean, we
never got a hearing on any of it and the
judge shortened I mean these clerks
shortened the time u and property.
>> It was the fourth scheduled sale of the
property, right?
>> When was it scheduled for?
>> It was the fourth scheduled sale.
>> Oh, that's true. That's true. But keep
in mind now timing of what this is
occurring in this event. We had the
October hurricane that took place in
2024. the city was all over a number of
different violations that were on that.
Unfortunately, the property by the
request of the plaintiffs had been put
under receiverhip and the receiver
wasn't attending any of those hearings,
wasn't going to any of the taking care
of any of these matters. So, my client
goes down and meets with the city. You
know, they go and discuss what plans are
going to have in the engineer and
everything else and get all the stuff
straight with the finance and everything
else, but the city's still saying, "You
got a receiverhip order here. you don't
do you have any authority to do
anything. So we made motions with the
court that which the opposing council
not this council but their under
underlying foreclosure council would not
agree with he would not agree to uh
allow us to go ahead and go forward and
do anything. So we're sitting there
going to the city and they're sitting
there saying well here's an order from
Judge Williams signed and this order
that they made and and the funny thing
about the receiverhip was crazy because
there was only one tenant in the
building. buildings just need to be
repaired. It was there was the one
tenant with the building uh all the city
wanted was in the plans in order to you
know get it permitted but it has to be
you know you have to make the request
for the permit has to be the owner but
in this case because we had the receiver
supporter we trying to get permission
from the receiver to do this stuff. Well
the first time we brought this whole
issue up to Judge Williams she did
continue the sale. The problem was the
30 days wasn't the 30 or 45 days that it
was that it was ultimately continued for
wasn't long enough because when we go
down there, we can't get anything done
because we as a even though we're the
owner, we can't do anything because the
receiver supporters there. And so we
filed all kinds of emergency motions to
have that receiver supporter rescended
or opened or done something so we could
do stuff. And we couldn't get
cooperation. The receiver wanted to sell
it to a third party and make a profit
off of it as opposed not met with the
city at all. hadn't attended any of the
hearings and my client's going down. I
can't do anything. My like hands are
tied and I've got this loan. I even put
up other property to go ahead and
refinance to pay this off. But the loans
contingent on at least having this the
city say we're, you know, we're dealing
with these with these code issues that
they very concerned about. And my client
is too because he's trying to meet that
requirement. But that's all backdrop.
What you know what the appeal is about
is the fact that the statute wasn't
followed at all and there is no case
that nor
>> it sounds to me like you've hitched your
wagon to the part of the statute that
says shall be heard right
>> the part that's about hearing
>> shall be heard yes
>> that's what you're hanging your hat on
>> yes yes and and
hang on just so I understand your
question you're also concerned that the
10day day period to object was not
honored.
>> Correct. It was two things.
>> It was eclipsed. See, this is what's
unusual about this case that I've never
encountered. Now, I've heard of people
filing objections and then the clerk
will dismiss it, right? And then you go
up and say that the certificate
shouldn't have been issued because the
objections were there. That's that's
kind of out there and and they always
say you reverse that, etc. That's not
usually a problem. But I've never seen
it where the clerk because they follow,
you know, they're rule oriented. They
follow that rule. They wait 10 days. You
get your sale and you get that 10 days.
If it wasn't for that extra provision
that was in there because the
certificate got issued on 34 and it
shouldn't have been issued at all. And
it happened because an order was
submitted to that added that extra
language to process it. And there was no
reason for that to be in the order
because the clerk processes the sale
under the rules no matter what. That
that's what they do. In other words, if
you got an order that says there's a
sale date, right,
they go forward that sale date unless
they get a call from the judge or an
order from the judge can. That's just
how it works. So, this order is entered
the 27th, which adds this extra language
no matter what. It should have just been
in a dialogue that that objection to
sale. it because the objection to sale
that's in the cl in the statute says
after the sale has been made you have 10
days from that sale being approved by
the clerk to file your objections which
has under regular and the statute
and
any I write in brief McN versus
Leisureville community they say flat out
it's reversed if you don't get a hearing
uh the mandate an evidentary hearing.
They cite the ragnar. Um they say if you
don't get one
>> are those on post post sale objections
versus pre-sale objections.
>> I'm sorry.
>> Post sale objections versus pre-sale
objections.
>> Yes, this for post sale. I agree.
>> And this was a pre-sale?
>> No, it was both. We filed the objection
beforehand because we wanted to get the
sale canled. We're assuming the judge
didn't grant it because she didn't call
on and cancel the sale. Then this order
is submitted and the order says it's
denied, but then it adds that extra
language. The clerk is directed to
process. So, we didn't even get to file
the objection to the post sale. Uh we
did file within 10 days just to cover
ourselves and we filed those other three
motions. I told you we did everything we
could do, but we couldn't deal with the
fact the clerk had already issued the
title. So then we asked for a hearing
and to vacate those and all those were
denied without a hearing. So we didn't
get the benefit of the 10day statute
that's required. We didn't get the
benefit of hearing or objection heard or
even filed right. We didn't get the any
motion or hearing whatsoever on any of
those subjects and even the one
beforehand was just was I'm assuming the
judges denied it but there was no
hearing on that either.
>> So Mr. Rubai, let's go through the
substance and looking at the objection
that you filed. If we look at the
substance of it, you indicated that you
had another buy. You're trying to
negotiate. You're trying you're working
toward, you know, you they're trying to
resolve this, but there's cases right on
point that said that that's not
sufficient
>> to stop a sale. How do you respond to
that?
>> Okay, here's what I respond to. Here's
what was going on. It is sufficient when
the property is unnaturally depressed.
And what we had here was a property
under a demolition order from the city
of St. Petersburg because of hurricane
damage in October while they had the
receiver in charge. And the receiver
didn't do anything to address those
problems. We obtained not only the
financing but obtained the engineer and
the contractor to get these things
fixed. We met with the city to address
all these problems and talked with them.
They were very receptive except they
said one thing. You have a receiverhip
order in place with their client. The
they're the ones that say that they're
in charge pursuant to this court order.
We need to know you have authority to do
this. So we can't do our hands are tied.
We cannot get receivers to cooperate
with us. We could not we had motions to
try to get that dissolved. So we have a
property that's depressed to the point
where it's not going to bring a correct
sale value. It's not going to bring
correct sal because of what the receiver
is doing and something that's in the
control of the mortgage mortgage and we
have proof they want to sell the
property to a third party and make money
off it off a commission. So, but we
didn't get a chance to present any
evidence of anything.
>> I So, how do you get around the fact
that this is not considered by the case
law to be a recognizable claim?
>> Because what do you mean? Who said you
can't judge it before you have a
hearing? Have a hearing.
>> There's cases out there. If we go to
this, let's just assume you've gotten
the hearing. Let's just assume all of
that. Let's get to the substance of it.
There's
>> But you can't we were entitled to file a
mo objection and have it heard an
evidentary hearing.
>> Okay, let's just assume we're h that the
hearing took place. What you have set in
your motion
does not appear to be a recognizable
claim under the case law. That's my
question to you. How do you get around
that? Well, I disagree. I think I think
that the forclosure quarter is a quarter
of equity and we have a commitment that
shows we pay the mortgage in full and
the only thing that's stopping us is
them. And they've stopped us to actions
that are they're improper. Surely we
would have a right. And if price was
depressed, nobody else bid because of
the condition of property that's created
by a hurricane while they're on their
watch. And they have insurance proceeds
that they haven't disclosed that were
there. Judge, there's a lot to this, but
I don't think we should be prejud what's
the good of procedural due process if
you can't even have a hearing on the
matter.
>> Well, let's talk about what a hearing is
because there's, as we all know from
reading the briefs, you guys have argued
back and forth. What is a hearing? What
is the right to be heard? It's simply
filing the motion and laying out your
complaint and the court reviewing that
and ruling on it. Have you been heard?
Have you received due process? a lot of
cases that say that's all you need.
There's a Supreme Court decision right
on point that says that's all you need
to be heard.
>> Well, not under the case
>> and I didn't see and and I'll let you
finish, but let me just leave this last
point. I saw nothing that that allowed
you to have an evidentiary hearing on
this. I saw no case that supports that.
So, finally, tell me about that.
>> Yes. Leisureville. Okay. This is Leisure
Larry versus Leiserville. write my brief
414 Southern 3rd 211 220 2025 and it's
followed by everybody else and then
Regnar follows leader Villia there's no
no disagreements I could find in the
districts or anything okay it says we
have interpreted these statutory
provisions to mandate an evidentary
hearing when a party timely objects the
foreclosure sale Ragnar versus Amtrust
to 111 in Ragnar defendants filed a
motion to vacate with certificate title
within 10 days of being filed The court
denied without an evidential hearing. We
reversed. We hold that the court to hear
objections. It must provide both notice
and opportunity for any interested party
to address these objections. We further
held is reversible error to deny a party
evidentary hearing to which the party is
entitled Ragnar and also sings purdue.
But the nature of your motion once again
brought forward issues which judge Kuzam
correctly pointed out. The case law says
these aren't reasons. These are not
cognizable reasons. I mean, the case law
is pretty clear on that. So, what's the
court supposed to do? Have an evidence
you're hearing on something that the
case law is bedrock solid on? This is
the reasons you've raised in your motion
do not equal a reason for us to cancel
the sale.
>> And Mr. Rub, before you respond, you're
about to get into your fiveminute
rebuttal. Okay.
>> Okay. Yes. Okay. So, let me clarify
this. The motion to cancel the sale is
not the same as the objection to the
sale that took place. The objection to
sale that took place is the one you're
definitely entitled to an evidential
hearing on completely. We didn't get the
10 days because the certificate was
issued before we could even get to that
objection. Although we filed an
objection, it wasn't within the 34
because the S title was already issued.
So, at that point, we had to get try to
get that vacated so we can even have the
sale. And all of those motions were
denied without a hearing.
>> All right. I'll give you you have four
minutes left for rebuttal. Okay. Thank
you, sir.
>> Mr. Donovan.
And while you're coming up, I see the
students have arrived. We are completing
the second case. And welcome, welcome to
the courthouse, Mr. Donovan.
>> Thank you. May I please the court? Chris
Donovan here on behalf of the Appal US
Bank on behalf as trustee of Velocity
Capital Commercial. Uh this court should
affirm for four reasons. First, the
arguments that have been raised in the
brief in the initial brief are not
preserved. They lack merit as well
because no hearing is absolutely
required in terms of like a live
in-person oral argument. Third, any
error was invited and fourth, any error
is harmless. Unless this court wants to
direct me into a specific issue, I'm
going to start at the top.
>> Let's go to the nature of of whether an
evidentiary hearing is required and if
so, under what circumstances.
>> I think the only circumstance that an
evidentiary hearing would be required is
if it if the objection or motion as the
case may be, if it's a motion to vacate
or an objection to the sale is actually
supported or is verified or supported by
some form of admissible evidence. In
fact, opposing council mentioned the
Leiserville in the in the Regnar
decisions and both of those involved
verified motions. In other words, there
was an actual affirmative presentation
of evidence or profering of evidence
that then led to a factual dispute that
had to have been resolved at an
evidentiary hearing. If it's just legal
arguments, then I think the s Supreme
Court precedent as well as precedent
from this court would suggest that uh a
a hearing or the right to be heard is
satisfied with simply a your written
motion or your written response. That's
the Watson versus Cotton Supreme Court.
>> Was there ever any uh um effort to set
the motion for hearing or request for a
hearing or or I mean help help me
understand that a little bit. the there
was never an attempt to actually set the
motion or any objection or motion for a
hearing. The closest that was requested
was that on on March 7th uh part of his
post sales objections, he did file a
document titled uh Nimbus' objection to
sale and request for evidentiary
hearing. And at the end of it, it
suggests that uh again wherefore clause,
you know, object to the sale and request
an evidentiary hearing on the issues
herein. But
>> and and if I may, didn't he also say
that the reason for that because he
needed time to repair the property so it
could obtain financing.
So that is not cognizable under the case
or sufficient for it for the court not
to allow this to go forward. Am I
correct in that?
>> You are correct, your honor. I'm going
to address that a little bit further.
Let me just finish explaining to Judge
Morris that simply asking for a hearing
or even an evidentiary hearing is
insufficient. You actually then take the
need to take the steps to set it for a
hearing, which was a problem that that
even the judge expressed frustration
with throughout this entire case with
because Nimbus would file motions
usually at the last minute and then
never set them for a hearing. But even
had he tried to make an attempt to set
it for a hearing, the trial judge would
have been correct to simply uh summarily
deny or review the motion and deny it.
That was sufficient to be heard,
especially under these circumstances
because as Judge Kuzam has pointed out,
the motion was ins was was not a
primapacia primmaaccia objection to a
foreclosure sale. was that I realized
the history of this case is five years
coming that it appears that it goes
forward then there's an objection goes
forward and the court was very very um
patient in resetting and resetting and
resetting and so this last time after 5
years of this property needed to be
foreclosed the court basically came to
the conclusion there's no recognizable
claim there's nothing at all and let the
seal go forward. Mr. Rub, I think that
this is reversible error. What is your
position?
>> My position is respectfully it's not
reversible error. Uh that even if there
was some hearing required or even if the
uh uh the clerk issued title
too soon before a full 10-day objection
uh period expired, the uh the objections
that he he sought relief on are not
recognized or not legally cognizable
objections to a sale. They all involved
issues that were well known often before
the actual foreclosure judgment, but
certainly well known before the uh
foreclosure sale. In fact, the third
request for uh a continuence or
objection to the third sale asked for
the same relief. They were asking for 30
to 45 days so that they could try to fix
all these issues and move forward or get
the permits issued and move forward with
the uh uh uh uh refinance. But the judge
probably should not the trial judge
probably should not have granted their
request then because it wasn't wasn't
verified. The evidence that they
attached and I put that in quotes was uh
was not authenticated. It was hearsay
etc. But the judge went out uh gave them
extra due process, I guess you'd say, by
going ahead and continuing the hearing
over the uh the lender's objection uh
and and gave them not only 30 days, but
gave them a full 45 days as my if I
recall correctly.
>> Let's um let's shift gear and talk about
the preservation of the issue of the
lack of a hearing in Pens Pensacola
versus King. You want to address that?
Have I given you enough to understand
what I'm asking?
>> I think Yes, sir. Yes. Yes, sir. The uh
uh Pensacola versus King basically
recognize that even if there's merit in
an argument, if you if if it's an issue
that was that that arose for the first
time in in uh uh the order, then you
have to file a motion for rehearing in
order to preserve the issue.
>> Was that done here?
>> There was a motion for reharing that was
filed, but it didn't actually argue that
a hearing was absolutely required under
this court or any other court's
precedent. So while yes, the prefuncter
motion for rehearing was filed which
largely uh uh reiterated a lot of these
objections that are legally
incognizable, they didn't actually raise
the arguments that they had raising on
appeal, which is that to be heard under
48.0318
requires a live physical oral argument.
Uh they didn't raise that argument nor
do they cite the schlissy versus city
financial which is from this court's
president. Uh but even had they cited
that this court's precedent seemed to
recognize in that case that a live
hearing is not required because that
particular case didn't involve an owner
objecting to a uh a foreclosure sale.
Rather it involved the lender trying to
vacate its own foreclosure sale which
was summarily granted without notice to
the third party purchaser. And so in
deciding this case I believe was
actually Judge Valante was the author.
They said, "You have to give notice to
the interested party and give them an
opportunity to be heard on the object on
the motion." And and they didn't. But
the court went on to state that, and I
quote, "We're not holding that a court
may only hear objections to a
foreclosure sale at an incourt
proceeding with council physically
present." The court didn't go that far
to to to the court. The court's uh uh
holding does not support the arguments
being raised even if they were preserved
by opposing council because if a
physical hearing is not required and at
a minimum any error is harmless because
the trial judge even if the title was
issued too soon the they still were
given the benefit of filing their
objection. They filed a motion for
reharing. They filed an objection and I
believe they filed another document
maybe a motion to vacate and it was all
within that 10day period. I think it was
on the ninth day. Now, I don't know why
they didn't quickly try to file it once
they issued the title. That would have
suggested a little more diligence, I
think, but they filed it on the ninth
day. Was technically ti time timely, but
then they didn't do anything with it.
They didn't set it for a hearing. It sat
there for another 20 days until the
court asked for uh uh proposed orders
and proposed orders were sent in and and
then they were still sat on for another
5 days before the court actually signed
a written order overruling those
objections uh in chambers without a
hearing without a physical hearing I
should say and then there was no motion
for rehearing on top of that which goes
back to Judge Morris's point on or at
least question about the Pensacola
versus King that had there been issues
that they wanted to raise about the lack
of physical hearing or oral argument.
They should have preserved those through
a motion for rehearing. So, absent
further questions from this court, I
will yield my time back to the bank.
>> Any more questions? Very good. Thank
you, Mr. Don. All right, Mr. Rubi, you
have just a few minutes for rebuttal.
>> First of all, your honor, if you if you
look at the record, you'll see that the
three orders that they mailed in to the
judge are the ones that they put a cover
letter to Gabriel Strand did not copy
me. So they mailed in three orders to
the judge denying all these without a
hearing by sending a coverlet and it's
right. Judge Judge Williams when she
filed something to give my
>> Are you saying you never got notice of?
>> Yes, that's what I'm saying.
>> So you weren't aware you never saw
>> after after it was entered I was aware
but they copied Gabriel's shrine. Now
see before that though when you council
was quite candid that I did file a
motion for rehearing to vacate the 227
order and I specifically stated in there
[clears throat] I filed this on 310.
Okay. And it said uh I said the the the
court filed objections to pre-sale at 10
a.m. and 265. And I put the clerk in I
said pliff's council create an order
that stated the clerk is instructed to
complete the necessary steps towards
issuance of a certificate of title and
dispersement of federal judgment and
pursue it to Florida law. Then I
compared it to what the actual rule says
about the order. If no objections to
sale are filed within 10 days after
filing the certificate of the sale, the
clerk shall file certificate of title.
And I move for rehearing saying that
what this order did, that exarty order
that was entered from the 26, it didn't
just deny my motion for re uh you know
to to to cancel the sale, which would
have been fine. It added that extra
paragraph in there to direct the clerk
to do the title move towards title and
because it was entered on the 27th even
though it was for something for the 26
this language is interpreted to issue
the title uh immediately. So what that's
what they did they issued on the 4th and
so and then I filed a rehering to all of
to to to that and the other and the
request for the hearing. Now Judge Kruz
to to correct me on something that's
very important here. There was no
contingencies on actually doing work to
get the financing for the property. All
the city wanted was that plans and
permits were in to do that. The problem
is my client couldn't get permits
without violating the receiverhip order
because the receivers have been placed
in charge of this property by the
receiverhip order. So my client is
handcuffed. He's not going to be accused
of violating a court order by signing
permits when the receiver and then when
we try to get the receiver involved, we
couldn't do it. He wouldn't show up to
any of these meetings or hearings. He
did not respond to the city. His agenda
was least to sell the property. We filed
motions to that effect. But I just want
to make it clear that the refinance
because the client, he actually put up a
whole another property at pledge for
this property to get the 1.7 million and
it included also a 1 million to ref to
refurbish the place to fix it. Okay. All
a lender wanted was because they don't
loan on buildings that have got open
code enforcement. They want proof that
you're going to address this. So my
client went down and met with the city.
Fine. We got all the things they wanted.
We couldn't do anything because we're
handcuffed by this receiverhip order and
they're GIS not the county I dealt with.
They would not allow us to do anything
because they had the receiverhip and the
receiver would not do anything
associated with the property. And once
again, I repeat, we're dealing with a
hurricane damage from October that had
to be addressed. That was the emergency
portion that the city was concerned
with. The city had there was a tree
didn't fall on here, you know. So, think
about this. You're an owner. You got the
property. You can't even bring your own
people out to do stuff because you're
violating receiver order. You go down
the city, make plans, they tell you what
you want. You go try to do it. You go
back to receiver supporter. That's all
created by the foreclosing party. So,
you know, and as far as it taking a long
time to do this, it was a co project to
begin with. Okay. They got a ton of
interest they're charging. That's how
they got up to a million7 which we were
going to pay. So, I'm not Mr. I know
you're you're approaching.
>> Good to see you.
>> Thank you, gentlemen. Yes. point just
from my I have an ethical obligation to
point out something. I forgot to do it
right there. In the brief, I might have
suggested that the property has been
demolished. Yeah, it's been resold in
being repaired, but it's not been
demolished.
>> I appreciate it for the record.
>> Thank you, Mr. D. Well, thank you both.
Thank you, gentlemen. Very interesting
case and well argued. Okay.